Rafi Chowdhury

Growth Engineer - Chowdhury's Digital

Northridge, CA rafi1220@gmail.com - (901)674-4629

Seven years of online experience as a growth hacker. Graduate of the University of Memphis with a Bachelors of Arts in Psychology with concentration in Cognitive Science. Founder/Co-founder of four start-up businesses. Responsible for company revenue in excess of \$100k/month.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Growth Engineer

Chowdhury's Digital - Los Angeles, CA - October 2014 to Present

Clients include Faithbaby, Inc., TEAM.Aero, unfunnel.com, IPS3web LLC, Easley Transportation, Beyond Steam Carpet Cleaning, Courtney Elmer, Sendoutnice.com, Pro Lock, ViAm Solutions, Healthcare Services Group, Nerium International, Senses Memphis, Pickle App, NRG Clean Power, The University of Memphis, and many more

- Manage internet platforms including social media and WordPress website
- Drive traffic to site and generate sales via content marketing, on-page optimization, social media engagement, & email marketing

Co-founder

myCampusHacks.com - Memphis, TN - August 2014 to Present

This social networking site is an up-and-coming startup focusing on improving a student's college experience

- Site received more than 150 registered users in the first month of launch
- Site was featured on several media outlets & was nominated to be featured on Inc. Magazine's "coolest college startups" for 2015

Growth Manager

Airplane - Beverly Hills, CA

Responsibilities

I serve as the Growth Manager for Airplane. My primary focus is business development as well as growth engineering. What is Airplane? Airplane is a growth agency. We help clients refine their products, expand their followings, and grow their customer bases using a combination of technical wizardry, product savvy, and shrewd marketing tactics. We offer a wide range of services, from SEO to social media growth to product design and product management. Unlike traditional marketing agencies, we believe that the growth of a company is about a lot more than simply producing buzz, which is why we do more than simply spread the word about your product. We surround your product with a constellation of refinements, optimizations, and integrations the sum total of is simple: more customers. More at www.airplanehq.com

Director of Digital Strategy

Wound Care Surgeons - Canoga Park, CA - September 2015 to November 2015

Growth hacker, email marketing, project management, ergonomics, content marketing, on-page seo, offpage seo, social media, brand management, digital marketing, link building, radio advertising, business development, and much more to increase the web presence of the company and reach the target audience

- Grew Facebook page to more than 2k fans in less than 1 week
- Grew Twitter to more than 65k followers in 2 weeks
- Managed email marketing campaign of more than 50k emails

Chess and Leadership Course Instructor

Chowdhury's Chess Leadership Program - Memphis, TN - August 2014 to August 2015

Chowdhury's Chess Leadership Program - Founder and Silent Owner (August 2014-August 2015)

- · Coach chess and leadership development courses in Memphis schools
- Spread the program to 8 schools locally
- The project's non-profit project, Caritas Village Chess Club was featured on ABC news in its 2nd week of launch

Founder and Owner

Chowdhury's Chocolate Checkmates - July 2014 to August 2015

Company has several active projects on chess leadership development and worked with 9 local schools

• Grew company to 7 employees and is projected to generate \$12k in revenue in first year

Founder

Chowdhury's Chocolate Checkmates - June 2014 to August 2015

Manufacture chocolate chess pieces, more than 200 units were sold

Certified to manufacture and sell food due to completion of Domestic Kitchen Online Training course

Digital Marketing Specialist

Total Concept - Memphis, TN - February 2015 to June 2015

Leading eCommerce project www.ecosignsandbanners.com

- Extra 10,000 targeted visitors to site resulting in positive ROI within first month
- Project components encompass, but are not limited to PPC, Google Adwords, SEM, SEO, Inbound Marketing, WordPress Development, Content Marketing, Google Analytics, Heat Map, Email Marketing, B to B marketing, Sales, Google Webmaster Tools, etc.
- Site ranks of Google for multiple high competition commercial intent keywords within the digital printing industry

Digital Marketing Specialist

Chowdhury's Digital - January 2015 to February 2015

Assisted with the marketing campaigns of politician George Flinn

- Built niche websites, managed and produced content for WordPress sites, created lead pages and squeeze pages, email campaigns using MailChimp, drove targeted traffic to niche sites,
- Used web analytics and marketing tools including Lead Pages, Vidlify, Fiverr.com, Click Funnels, Google Analytics, keywordtool.io, Tweepi, and Buzzsumo

Research Assistant

Institute of Intelligent Systems - Memphis, TN - 2013 to 2014

Researched under Dr. Art Graesser's lab with PhD student Brent Morgan on his dissertation on mood and multitasking

Wrote for a Chess Intelligent Tutoring System joint venture with Brent Morgan under his company MMTech

Marketer & Tournament Director

Mid-South Chess - 2007 to 2014

Worked as head chess instructor/promoter since 2008

- Taught and promoted chess at various local schools and in the community
- Ran and organized chess tournaments both locally and nationally
- · Grew the tournament to include more schools over the years
- Responsible for company's revenue growth to in excess of \$100K

Specialized Sales Clerk

SeaWorld Orlando - Orlando, FL - May 2013 to July 2013

Sold \$400+ worth of merchandise on any given day around the park

· Leading sales representative for the company

Tournament Director & Vendor

Cajun Chess - Memphis, TN - 2011 to 2012

Sold more than \$6000 worth merchandise at several single tournaments

Ran chess tournaments consisting of more than 100 players

SOCIAL MEDIA:

Facebook: www.facebook.com/rafichowdhury.entrepreneur

Twitter: www.twitter.com/_rafichowdhury
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/rafichowdhury

Google+: https://plus.google.com/+RafiChowdhury1406/posts

YouTube: www.youtube.com/user/RafiChowdhury1

Website: www.rafichowdhury.com - 30k unique visitors/month with Alexa Rank 70k

Managing Partner

Social Gab, LLC - Los Angeles, CA - August 2015

I am a managing partner of Social Gab

- I focus on business development as well as production.
- I handle all things business and marketing.
- My primary areas of focus include Business Development, Operations, Brand Management, Production, Lead Generation, Community Relations, Market Research, Recruitment, Project Management, and much more

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Arts in Psychology

The University of Memphis May 2010 to May 2014

SKILLS

SEO, Linkedin, Facebook, Twitter, Growth hacking, Growth engineering, Google Analytics, Google Docs, Google Adwords, Google Webmaster Tools, Google Chrome, Google+, Google, Search Engine Optimization, Marketing, Online Marketing, Sem, Office, Excel, Business Development, Marketing Research, Marketing Strategy, Wordpress, Web Design, Web Development, Javascript, Coaching, Lead Generation, Market Analysis, Keynote, Public Speaking, Management, Graphic Design

LINKS

http://www.chowdhurysdigital.com

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Media Appearances and References:

http://weirdentrepreneurs.com/podcast/rafi-chowdhury/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafichowdhury

http://www.rafichowdhury.com/

https://www.facebook.com/rafichowdhury.entrepreneur

https://twitter.com/_rafichowdhury

http://www.stephenesketzis.com/interviews/rafi-chowdhury-23-year-old-entrepreneur-digital-marketer-says-

videos-infographics-and-webinars-are-the-next-big-thing/

https://www.youtube.com/user/RafiChowdhury1

https://plus.google.com/+RafiChowdhury1406/posts

http://streetsideconvos.com/2014/12/17/rafi-chowdhury/

http://start-up-booster.com/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury-great-tips-from-multiple-entrepreneur/

http://sdasia.co/2014/10/25/campus-hacks-chess-pieces-story-rafi-chowdhury/

http://www.voicesofmarketing.com/written-interviews/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury/

http://paychecktopassion.com/blog/rafi-chowdhury-business-like-chess/

http://iviewz.com/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury-founder-of-chowdhurys-and-co-founder-of-

mycampushackschowdhury/

http://withfivequestions.blogspot.com/2015/03/meet-rafi-chowdhury-entrepreneur.html

http://noragouma.com/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury-eco-signs-and-banners/

http://meritpages.com/Rafi-Chowdhury/113766

http://www.chess.com/members/view/RafiChowdhury

http://www.stephenesketzis.com/interviews/rafi-chowdhury-23-year-old-entrepreneur-digital-marketer-says-

videos-infographics-and-webinars-are-the-next-big-thing/

http://chowdhurysdigital.com/

http://www.kicktrag.com/projects/1005022781/mycampushacks-social-networking-site-for-college-s/

http://www.localmemphis.com/news/local-good-news-chess-at-caritas-village

http://rafichowdhury.com.cutestat.com/

http://www.dailyhelmsman.com/archives/website-aimed-to-guide-u-of-m-students-through-campus/

article_c5389de1-2653-575a-8ea6-dfda0cf0e30f.html

http://www.simandan.com/?p=14990

http://www.ips3web.com/online-marketing-for-your-company/

http://www.manta.com/cp/mx4snn2/547a58047a29dad011dfd7fe/chowdhury-s-chess-leadership-program

http://www.globalyuppiestyle.com/entrepreneurial-and-life-advice-from-memphis-digital-marketing-guru-rafi

http://mychesscoach.net/

http://mychesscoach.net/

https://unfunnel.com/seo-keyword-strategy/

http://vintagemediagroup.com/dotcom-entrepreneur-lives-home-mama/

http://www.pinstopin.com/rafi-quotes/